Guide to the Frank Deutscher Company records 1978.143
Brooklyn Historical Society
Frank Deutscher Company records
1905-1962
Brooklyn Historical Society
Murphy, Robert
Frank Deutscher Company
Gray-Pyle Real Estate Company
1978.143
0.1 Linear Feet in three folders.
Property appraisals, sale contracts, and other documents from the records of the Frank Deutscher Company, a real estate firm located at 16 Court Street in Brooklyn.
Box A0033
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Murphy, 1976.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series by type. Series 1: Edison Electric Illuminating Company appraisals is arranged by parcel number. Series 2: Sales contracts and Series 3: Other materials are arranged chronologically.
Historical note
The Frank Deutscher Company was a real estate firm located at 16 Court Street in Brooklyn.
Howard C. Pyle and Company was founded in 1904 by Howard C. Pyle and George H. Gray, and the company's name was changed to the Gray-Pyle Real Estate Company in 1919.
Related Materials
Gray-Pyle Real Estate Company records (1977.315)
Inapunch real estate collection (1986.035)
Downtown Brooklyn real estate appraisals (1980.009)
Brooklyn Real Estate Board magazines and bulletins (ARC.177)
Brooklyn, Queens, and Long Island real estate brochure collection (ARC.296)
Scope and Contents
Property appraisals, sale contracts, and other documents from the records of the Frank Deutscher Company, a real estate firm located at 16 Court Street in Brooklyn. The appraisals primarily relate to 20 parcels of land owned by the Edison Electric Illuminating Company (1906) and were apparently conducted by Howard C. Pyle and Company. The sale contracts date to the early 1920s and relate mostly to properties in Brooklyn Heights and Downtown Brooklyn, though two properties in Midwood are also included. Other materials include information about the Bay Ridge Theatre property on 3rd Avenue and a pamphlet from Edward Lyons, Inc. listing properties for sale.
Deeds -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Mortgages -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Architectural drawings; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Real property -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Midwood (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Appraisals (records); Contracts; Contracts -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real estate business -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real estate investment -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real property; Real property auctions -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real property -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real property -- Ownership -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Real property -- Valuation; Real property -- Valuation -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Murphy, Robert; Edison Electric Illuminating Co. of New York
- Series 1: Edison Electric Illuminating Company appraisals, 1906 (Box A0033, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Appraisals of 20 parcels owned by the Edison Electric Illuminating Company prepared by Howard C. Pyle and Co.
  - Parcels 1 and 2
    Gold and John Streets, waterfront.
  - Parcel 3
    Pearl Street near Willoughby Street.
  - Parcel 4
    Rapelye Street near Van Brunt Street.
  - Parcel 5
    Hicks Street near Huntington Street.
  - Parcel 6
    Carroll Street between 6th and 7th Avenues, near 6th.
  - Parcel 7
    Sumpter Street near Stone Avenue.
  - Parcels 8 and 9
    Atlantic Avenue near Nostrand Avenue.
  - Parcel 10
    Lexington Avenue near Grand Avenue.
  - Parcel 11
    DeKalb Avenue, Middleton Street near Harrison Avenue.
  - Parcel 12
    Lorimer Street near Harrison Avenue.
  - Parcel 13
    Ainslee, Rodney and Hope Streets.
  - Parcel 14
    Myrtle Avenue and Troutman Street.
  - Parcel 15
    Bay Ridge, 66th Street near waterfront.
  - Parcel 16
    West 12th Street, Coney Island.
  - Parcel 17
    Neptune Avenue and West 20th Street, John Y. McCane plant.
  - Parcel 18
    West 5th Street near Neptune Avenue.
  - Parcel 19
    Varick Avenue stone yard. Meserole Street, Stewart Avenue, Montrose Avenue and Varick Avenue.
  - Parcel 20
    Carroll Street near 4th Avenue.
- Series 2: Sale contracts (Box A0033, Folder 2)
  - 34 Sidney Place, March 29 1920
    Elizabeth Callender to Louis and Minnie Hansen.
  - 43 Garden Place, April 22 1920
    Lilla A. Blood to Sylvia Seaton.
  - 12 Garden Place, May 11 1920
    Mary J. Lutfy to Frank S. Murty.
  - 42 Garden Place, May 24 1920
    Isaac Kleinfeld to Grace Carroll.
  - 46 Garden Place, May 24 1920
    John J. O'Keefe to Gilbert B. Ferris.
  - 35 Garden Place, May 24 1920
    Harold and Elsie Bunker to Gilbert B. Ferris.
  - 40 Garden Place, May 27 1920
    Mary A. Dall to Henrietta W. Wynn.
  - 16 Garden Place, June 8 1920
    Cornelia A. Bleecker to Gilbert B. Ferris.
  - 29 Garden Place, June 11 1920
    Miriam Cannon to Gilbert B. Ferris.
  - 39 Garden Place, June 19 1920
    Michael Freije to Grace Carroll.
  - 27 Garden Place, June 24 1920
    Daisy Sproule to Oliver E. Yale.
  - 54 Court Street, March 10 1921
    Hazel Pyle Hanford to Sagamore Lunch, Inc.
  - 381 Bridge Street, October 6 1921
    Frederick J. Wustl to Frederick and Adolf Haedrich.
  - Willoughby Street near Bridge Street, October 6 1921
    Reno Realty Company to Frederick and Adolf Haedrich.
  - 38 Monroe Place, April 17 1922
    Mary Ughetta to Marie Rogers.
  - 120 Pierrepont Street, July 21 1922
    Syb and Som Company to Agnes Florien Mullin.
  - 159 Joralemon Street and 105 Clinton Street, October 31 1922
    William Jarvis Turner to Traders Exchange, Inc.
  - 67 Midwood Street, December 1923-February 1924
    Ida Magie to Edward Fox.
  - 8 Sidney Place, January 31 1924
    Prospect Park West Construction Co. to Adolph Markman.
  - 242 Midwood Street, July 23 1924
    Luqueer Holding Corporation to William J. Magee.
  - 493 State Street, December 11 1924
    Ellen M. Williamson to Nellie McGrath.
- Series 3: Other materials (Box A0033, Folder 3)
  - Letter regarding appraisal of 184-186 Montague Street, 1907
  - Bay Ridge Theatre, 7114 3rd Avenue, 1962
    Map of lot and information on public auction.
  - Edward Lyons, Inc. pamphlet, undated
    Lists various properties for sale, including many on DeKalb Avenue, Classon Avenue, Emerson Place and Union Place.